They told us it would be impossible to make this movie. They told us it would be
impossible for you to watch it. We hope nothing is impossible.
The Day After is a science fiction, drama, tv movie
film directed by Nicholas Meyer.
In the mid-1980s, the U.S.
is poised on the brink of nuclear war.
This shadow looms over the residents of a small town in
Kansas as they continue their daily lives.
Russell Oakes maintains his busy schedule at the hospital, Denise Dahlberg prepares for
her upcoming wedding, and Stephen Klein is deep in his graduate studies.
When the unthinkable happens and the bombs come down, the town's
residents are thrust into the horrors of nuclear winter.
Dr. Russell Oakes, played by Jason Robards.
Nurse Nancy Bauer, played by JoBeth Williams.
Stephen Klein, played by Steve Guttenberg.
Jim Dahlberg, played by John Cullum.
Joe Huxley, played by John Lithgow.
Eve Dahlberg, played by Bibi Besch.
The Day After is a 1983 American television film directed by Nicholas Meyer.
The war film postulates a fictional conflict between NATO and the Warsaw Pact over Germany that rapidly
escalates into a full-scale nuclear exchange between the United States and the Soviet Union.
The action itself focuses on the residents of Lawrence, Kansas, and Kansas City,
Missouri, and several family farms near American missile silos.
The cast includes JoBeth Williams, Steve Guttenberg, John
Cullum, Jason Robards, and John Lithgow.
The film was written by Edward Hume and produced by Robert Papazian.
More than 100 million people, in nearly 39 million households, watched the film when
it first aired on November 20, 1983, on the ABC television network.
With a 46 rating and a 62% share of the viewing audience during the initial broadcast, the film was the seventh-highest-rated
non-sports show until then, and in a 2009 Nielsen TV Ratings list was one of the highest-rated television films in US history.
The film was broadcast on Soviet state television in 1987, during the
negotiations on Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces Treaty.
The producers demanded that the Russian translation conform to the original
script and that the broadcast not be interrupted by commentary.
The film explores themes of high school, environmental
protection agency, nuclear war, isolation, darkness.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and emotional.